GAGANDEEP SINGH

Sector 61, Royal Towers Society, Noida – 201301 Uttar Pradesh gagandeep509.singh@gmail.com Contact: + 91 - 9718148657

Objective

To learn and grow in a professional environment-enhance my skills and broaden my perspective. As a focused individual, I like working collaboratively with people in a team environment and get an opportunity to utilize all my

PHP knowledge and skills to benefit the organization

Summary

Every of superiors in Web Cite Desire Development and Deplement using DUD LITAL CCC. InvaCorint on

5 years of experience in Web Site Design, Development and Deployment using PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript or jQuery.

Extensive hand-coding experience in PHP 5, HTML / CSS / JavaScript / AJAX.

Programming Enterprise level PHP sites from scratch update and maintain current sites and scripts.

Database Design and Maintenance My SQL

Open Source Customization.

Implementation of stable mobile app Push Notifications using FCM and GCM (Android) as well as APNS (IOS).

Work Skills

.....

Operating System: Windows and Linux

Languages/Scripting: PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, cron job set up

Frameworks/CMS: Laravel, Codelgniter, Zend, Cake PHP(Beginner), Magento(Beginner), Wordpress(Beginner)

Web Authoring Tools: NetBeans, Dream Weaver

Database: MySQL with procedures, triggers and events

App/Web Server: Amazon AWS, Amazon EC2, Amazon S3Bucket, Knowledge about scope of Amazon AWS

server related features (Attended server related training/workshop from Amazon).

Qualification

- High School from CBSE Board in 2008
- Intermediate from CBSE Board in 2010
- Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science & Engineering), UPTU

Job Experience

Sr. PHP Developer

Techmoweb Experts Pvt. Ltd. (Present)

Company Product for online games on web & app.

Product based company has focus on their product development and maintenance. It has products like Togel & Poker games. I've been working on Togel product as Sr. PHP Developer currently and assisting in test cases for the Togel product.

Sr. PHP Developer

Benepik Technology Pvt. Ltd. (Aug 2016 – Aug 2017)

Company Product for Employee communication as well as employee beneficiary app.

Product based company made focus on their product development and maintenance. It had been a customized product for our individual clients, including product features as well as some custom modules and add-on functionality added on client demand.

Name of reputed clients that I've worked for with different requirements and custom add-ons of these clients in our product:

Role: Leaded Team for these projects.

Haier Barclays Manav Rachna University Aviva Insurance Vikas Group

PHP Developer

Parangat Technologies Pvt Ltd (Jan 2016 – Aug 2016)

Project Title. With-Live - Chatting app

Role: PHP Developer, Team Size: 3 Environment: PHP(core), MySql.

Project Details: Chatting app having features like one to one chat, group chat, broadcast chat. Also user can send images, docs or videos in chat. Also can create update & delete group chats similar to whatsapp.

Project Title. Doubtsclass - Notes & Q/A service provider app

Role: PHP Developer, Team Size: 4

Environment: PHP (Zend), MySql, Amazon s3 Bucket, Ajax, jQuery / Javascript

Project Details: Modifying a web application for clients for providing notes and Q&A sessions to registered as well as guest users. Registered institutes or teachers provide notes to their registered students and also students can ask queries to their teachers or favorite teachers by buying credits for Q&A services.

Project Title. Trackrecord – Social and Online Music player app

Role: PHP Developer, Team Size: 3

Environment: PHP(CodeIgniter), MySql.

Project Details: Online music player app with features of like, share and comment as social and creating personal playlist and also can add soundcloud playlists as well and also creating events both public & private members and also invite users to perform on those events.

PHP Developer

Techahead Software (Jul 2014 – Dec 2015)

Project Title. Acre Guru – Residential society service provider and property listing app

Role: PHP Developer, Team Size: 8

Environment: PHP(CodeIgniter), MySql, Amazon s3 Bucket, HTML,CSS, Ajax, jQuery / Javascript Project Details: It is a platform for property listing. It helps you out to view the service providers on map and make an order to the service provider closest to your place to save time. It has a great network of efficient service providers in most efficient way. It helps you out to have your task done from paying dues, selling furniture, joining a car pool, discuss local and society issues with neighbors, getting circulars from society etc.

Project Title. Fit Gang - Social fitness platform that lets you engage and track your fitness app

Role: PHP Developer, Team Size: 9

Environment: PHP(CodeIgniter), MySql, Amazon s3 Bucket, HTML, CSS, Ajax, jQuery / Javascript

Project Details: FitGang is a fitness based social platform for users to track their fitness and also discover

health clubs on the basis of location proximity, Budget, Facilities – like No. of branches, upcoming health clubs,

no of equipment's, Category – Dance, Yoga etc.

Project Title. Fruity - Social Networking app for snap addicts

Role: PHP Developer, Team Size: 7

Environment: PHP(CodeIgniter), MySql.

Project Details: Fruity is social networking platform where user can create a profile and upload any photo of their choice. Photo will be liked on a scale of 5-10 by others and the ratings are added to the profile score which are ranked on leaderboards. The users can battle it out with other users on the leaderboard for the number 1 spot. Users can also create custom leaderboards for their friends to battle privately. Random fruity search option in the app will allow the users to search for specific profiles and rate them.

Project Title. Hello Stranger – Simply chat with similar strangers

Role: PHP Developer, Team Size: 5

Environment: PHP(Codelgniter), MySql, Amazon s3 Bucket.

Project Details: Fruity is social networking platform where user can create a profile and upload any photo of their choice. Photo will be liked on a scale of 5-10 by others and the ratings are added to the profile score which are ranked on leader boards. The users can battle it out with other users on the leader board for the number 1 spot. Users can also create custom leader boards for their friends to battle privately. Random fruity search option in the app will allow the users to search for specific profiles and rate them.

Hobbies

- Listening to music and reading about history
- Playing video games and athletic sports
- Traveling & exploring new places.

Personal Information

Father's Name Ranbir Singh

Date of Birth 21st July 1992

Gender Male
Religion Sikh
Marital Status Single

Language Known English, Punjabi and Hindi

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

{Gagandeep Singh}